<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-05T12:01:11+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">lower case opinions</title><entry><title type="html">acceptable transgressions | body hair &amp;amp; your greatest weakness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/acceptable-transgressions" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="acceptable transgressions | body hair &amp; your greatest weakness" /><published>2019-07-02T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/acceptable-transgressions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/acceptable-transgressions">&lt;p&gt;One of the basic interview prep pieces of advice is to rehearse an answer for “what’s your greatest weakness?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; dislike this question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So often it’s asked because the interviewer has pulled it from a list of things to ask in interview, and so often it’s answered with something glib and unrevealing. You ask the question, I say the thing I prepared, we move on. You haven’t learnt anything about me, you haven’t prepared for receiving this info, you aren’t going to work with me to plan how we mitigate or improve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t dispute that it’s useful to know someone’s skill-gaps, to verify their level of self-awareness, to gauge how humble they are, to learn how receptive they are to feedback from others, to understand their learning &amp;amp; self-development plans and approach. But with this question, and the way it’s deployed, you won’t get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the many many many thinkpieces and advice snippets for how to share your Greatest Weakness focus on palatable gaps. Say, maybe you’re a perfectionist. Maybe you just care too much. Maybe you love to help others so sometimes have to work long hours to achieve your goals. Maybe you have a visionary understanding of where the industry is about to pivot to and you’re only just starting to get ahead of the curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like body hair. Women’s body hair in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-body-hair-that-were-allowed&quot;&gt;The body hair that we’re allowed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We celebrate women (white cis women who are conventionally attractive according western beauty norms) when they transgress the ideal of hairlessness. Hey &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teenvogue.com/story/halsey-unshaven-armpits-rolling-stone-cover&quot;&gt;Halsey didn’t shave her underarms&lt;/a&gt; and she’s on the cover of Rolling Stone with her armpits out, that’s a powerful feminist move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even unshaven legs are a symbol of non-conforming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are heaps of “my story” pieces in women’s magazines both online and offline about why someone chose not to remove all their body hair BUT they are all focussed on the acceptable transgressions, the palatable decisions to diverge from the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ladies, if you’re “beautiful” enough, you can decide to not shave your legs or underarms. That’s the message we take away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet we don’t even mention upper lip hair; toe hair; that weird long hair that grows out of the middle of your forehead; nipple hair; back hair. And we CERTAINLY don’t engage with the idea that maybe it’s a bold feminist choice to leave the hair to grow as it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re so focussed on performing vulnerability, performing boldness, that we don’t dig deep and truly examine these things and benefit from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I want to remove my bodyhair? If only partly, can I focus on the parts that are irritating or time consuming, not the parts deemed socially permissible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-greatest-weaknesses-that-were-allowed&quot;&gt;The Greatest Weaknesses that we’re allowed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find ourselves in the same position when confronted with “what’s your greatest weakness?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are weaknesses we are allowed to have, allowed to share. And others that we can’t touch on even when they’re true, even when they’re important for our future manager to know, even when we’re still eminently hirable with these weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody is perfect, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I want to acknowledge my imperfections? If so, can I do so in a way that imparts useful directional info to a future manager? Is it not also harmful to me to perform invulnerability when I’ll need this person, this future manger, to support and guide me to level up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please stop asking “what’s your greatest weakness”. Please stop preparing glib answers. Let’s have a real conversation instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-instead&quot;&gt;What instead?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what you want with your body hair, folks, and stop casting judgement on others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, perhaps more pertinently, interview better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the questions I’ve used to achieve the goal that I think we ought to be aiming for when we consider asking this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what have you learnt about yourself in the last year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how would you manager describe you? Would your coworkers say anything different? Why do you think that?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What skills do you want to learn or improve here?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you join us, how would you want us to support your personal development?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the most useful feedback you’ve received? How have you used that feedback?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we’re building a well-rounded team, what skills should we look for in the next person we hire to work alongside you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you want to get better at?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you approach new problems that our completely out of your comfort zone? Do you have an example?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about a time when you got stuck at work. How did you get past it? Who helped you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking back at the job ad for this role, which parts do you think you’ll find most challenging?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviewees: flip it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick one of the above, answer that instead, then ask the person interviewing you how they have supported someone in mitigating or overcoming their biggest weakness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we can have real conversations, learn things about each other, and stop doing the dance where we say things for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One of the basic interview prep pieces of advice is to rehearse an answer for “what’s your greatest weakness?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">connective learning | mis-spending my training budget</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/connective-learning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="connective learning | mis-spending my training budget" /><published>2019-06-30T09:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T09:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/connective-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/connective-learning">&lt;p&gt;I decided to change jobs a couple of months ago, so spent a bunch of time interviewing and really learnt a lot about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few pieces of interesting feedback that were remarkably consistent across every person I interviewed with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a different perspective / think about problems differently to them.
This has been a recurring theme in feedback from people I work with too (and friends!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is unclear what how I approach my own personal development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this particularly interesting because I consider myself to be a curious person who spends a lot of time learning, and I really value the pursuit of learning - it’s fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I concluded that I need to get better at articulating how I think about learning: particularly as a People leader, where I’ll be responsible for helping everyone in the company learn and develop! So I’ve spent some time considering this and uncovered the empiric truth of how I approach learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this exercise really helpful, so am sharing here both the way that I thought about this, and the conclusions I came to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem-finding-problem-solving&quot;&gt;Problem finding, problem solving&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was fortunate enough to sneak into some of the talks at the exceptional Lead Developer conference in London. One really stuck with me - it hugely clarified something I’d been thinking about but hadn’t developed a mental model for yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please either pause and watch it:  or at least open it in a new tab and promise me you’ll watch it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to earlier this month, when I picked up Dan Pink’s book To Sell Is Human. In one of the chapters, he pitches to his reader that the modern world of selling requires becoming a problem &lt;em&gt;finder&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Problem finders] sort through vast amounts of information and inputs, often from multiple disciplines; experiment with a variety of different approaches; are willing to switch directions in the course of a project; and often take longer than their counterparts to complete their work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;becoming-a-good-cook&quot;&gt;Becoming a good cook&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to this morning. I’m on my way to a knife skills course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like food. I enjoy the creativity of making something delicious, and the gratification of spending time making a tangible thing then consuming it. There’s something around the instant feedback loop there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first moved out of my parents’ house and became responsible for feeding myself, I concluded that I needed to become a good cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of caveats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I didn’t really learn to cook at home; my mum wasn’t super experimental, so taught me the basics but in a very intuitive way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I find it hard to follow recipes - it limits my understanding of the WHY (&amp;amp; reminds me of learning cookery at school where I spent about a year fucking up white sauce and pastry because I didn’t &lt;em&gt;get it&lt;/em&gt; enough to know what was important and how to fix mistakes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I set about achieving this goal of &lt;em&gt;becoming a good cook&lt;/em&gt; through various different strands - assembling the building blocks or grammar &amp;amp; syntax of food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of the things I undertook, semi-deliberately, over the last 15(!!) years in order to become someone who can now cook well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sought out nice restaurants within my budget and ate things I didn’t know how to cook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read menus and collected themes of ingredients that people use together regularly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;started drinking my way through red wine and reading the labels to understand what I liked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read a paper about soil, sun and climate change in relation to wine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spent a few hours browsing in a book store to understand what combinations of foods cropped up in which geographic areas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read more about climate, soil and local vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;moved in with a man who has strong feelings about texture in food&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;started trialling substitutions in my regular dishes to see what worked well (and what was actually disastrous or inedible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nikisegnit.com/the-flavour-thesaurus&quot;&gt;The Flavour Thesaurus&lt;/a&gt; by Nikki Segnit and read it cover to cover to cement the themes of flavour pairings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watched my scientist sister cooking a roast dinner and how she thinks about heat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had a baby and observed his approach to self-feeding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read a series of papers about heat, which materials conduct, pre-heating, effect of moisture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read The Omnivore’s Dilemma by Michael Pollan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read the counterargument to this, Eating Animals by Jonathan Safran Foer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sniffed a bunch of spices at a spice market on vacation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;took up origami (in the hope it would help me build the discipline of recipe-following!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saltfatacidheat.com/&quot;&gt;Salt Fat Acid Heat&lt;/a&gt; by Samin Nosrat (twice)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read a bunch of vegan blogs to get a better understanding of the politics of food&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read Sight Smell Touch Taste Sound by Sybil Kapoor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;signed up for a knife skills class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bought (but haven’t read yet!) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nikisegnit.com/lateral-cooking&quot;&gt;Lateral Cooking&lt;/a&gt;, also by Nikki Segnit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these things have help me build up a solid foundation on which I can build connections, understanding the history and politics and geography of food; cuisine, nutrition, balance; how the senses interplay in eating; the science behind how certain processes work.
Which had given me a super strong, well-informed approach to building meals that &lt;em&gt;just work&lt;/em&gt; and can be cooked free-hand (because while my origami game is strong I still rebel whenever I attempt to follow a recipe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;another-shorter-example&quot;&gt;Another, shorter example&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken a similar approach to art:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hanging out in galleries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning where pigments come from&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;studying aesthetics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading The Story of Art by EH Gombrich&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;modelling for life drawing classes and listening intently (in between naps)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading some pop science articles to understand how humans perceive colour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;taking a course on contemporary art philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading about the history of colour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visiting more galleries &amp;amp; exhibitions with engaged friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;deliberately seeking out artists I love in curated exhibitions whose topics are unfamiliar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;taking up painting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;picking up some paint by numbers versions of famous paintings to understand how to paint nuanced colours &amp;amp; shade (I freaking love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://faradayscienceshop.com/collections/van-go-paint-by-number-kits/&quot;&gt;Van-Go kits&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visiting yet more galleries….&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a web of perspectives, drawing connections between them, identifying and honing in on the empty spaces and starting to sketch in what’s missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-what-does-this-mean&quot;&gt;So what does this mean?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This connective dabbling, building a web of learning and perspective, is how learning through my career has worked too. Getting a deep understanding of analogous &amp;amp; adjacent spaces and combining these in between from a slightly askew perspective to end up with something built from scratch, ground-up, without completely ignoring conventional wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much of this is because I ended up studying philosophy for three years, and so dig deeply into epistemology, theory of knowledge and interlocking web-based models of truth and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the startup world, we have a huge opportunity to do things differently. We can reexamine existing models and fill out the gaps, we can dig deeper to find the problem that actually matters and build a solution that works for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conventional business, if learning is a priority at all it’s very linear. It’s relatively easy to take a course that is obviously directly related to your role and will obviously directly impact your performance. But this isn’t how everyone learns. I’d love to build a world where we make space for people to learn in this connective way. Where &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; your receptionist should take a user experience design course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I think if I told most companies that to help me learn to cook I need a JSTOR subscription, a topographical map of Europe and a case of wine, they’d laugh. But here we are; so why not?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I decided to change jobs a couple of months ago, so spent a bunch of time interviewing and really learnt a lot about myself.</summary></entry></feed>