<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-20T14:45:15+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">lower case opinions</title><author><name>maria campbell</name></author><entry><title type="html">flexible working / dolly parton was right you know</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/flexible-working" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="flexible working / dolly parton was right you know" /><published>2019-07-20T09:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-20T09:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/flexible-working</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/flexible-working">&lt;p&gt;I’m continually baffled by tech companies who set fixed working hours and expect everyone to work from the same place all the time. It feels old fashioned, in an industry that prides itself on innovation. And I’ve seen the advantages of flexible working play out - in terms of organisational effectiveness, as well as hiring &amp;amp; retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’ve worked part-time, I’ve worked from home 1-3 days a week, I’ve worked fully remote from an apartment in Istanbul, and I’ve managed a globally distributed team spanning three offices in seven timezones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first tech startup role, which I started just after my child’s first birthday, was a four-day week: three days in the office, one day of completely unpredictable hours split across two days’ naptimes, evenings and stolen hours at the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked in companies where there’s a designated work-from-home day each week; I’ve also worked in a globally distributed company where every team was distributed across at least two timezones with different public holidays and there were exactly zero hours each week which fell into ‘normal business hours’ for everyone in the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many advantages to flexible working, both for the individual and the company. We talk a lot about the advantages to the individual, and the corollary that happier people means better retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shifting to flexible work requires some organisational changes, all of which end up being advantageous to the overall health of the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ability-to-hire-a-more-diverse-team&quot;&gt;Ability to hire a more diverse team&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that a diverse team is a better team, so I’m not going to spend time making the business case or explaining why this is a good thing. Let’s talk instead about how flexible working helps you build a more diverse (and therefore better) team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents are the obvious beneficiaries of flexible working. Childcare is expensive and seems to be predicated on everyone working 9-5 with zero commute. Women with children typically shoulder the brunt of childcare responsibility in families, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spans out further to everyone with adult dependents or caring responsibilities, too. In general, people of colour have more dependents than white people, so benefit even further from the flexibility to take a sibling or parent to a medical appointment or other activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flexible working also generally works better for folks with disabilities. Commuting during rush hours with a physical disability? Chronic illnesses often require relatively high amounts of contact time with medical specialists, and your stressed &amp;amp; depressed employees will likely want to see a therapist every week, all of which needs to take place during standard business hours. Open-plan offices are really not well designed for neurodivergence (or arguably neurotypicals, though my feelings about office design are firmly out of scope here).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;better-communication&quot;&gt;Better communication&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flexible working is a forcing function to fix your internal comms rhythms and routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the “joys” of a fully co-located team with set hours is that you can have meetings whenever you like, and you can always just tap the person you want to talk to on the shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However this has a lot of downsides, especially once you’re communicating at any kind of scale - and even more downsides when you’re doubling your company size every 6-9 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, the best ways to improve your company’s internal communication effectiveness involve both (1) disregarding the perceived advantages of having everyone all in the same place at the same time and (2) doing the thing that you are annoyed you need to do to accommodate flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good communication that works for flexibility means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;better documentation: storing knowledge in writing somewhere searchable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;better meeting rhythms: no ad-hoc chats pulling folks out of what they’re doing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;more compressed meeting schedule: fewer 15-min gaps where nothing really useful can be achieved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;right meeting participants: wait till &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; relevant folks can attend, not just whoever is nearest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“could this meeting be an email?” or, fewer update meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;asynchronous decision-making in writing (through slack or email or a shared doc with comments) (NB this also helps folks who like to ponder or research before deciding)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stronger organisational memory: discussions are more searchable, less reliant on hoping you can find someone who was there and remembers why you did this particular thing last year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arguably you should do all these things &lt;em&gt;even if&lt;/em&gt; your company is (and always will be) fully co-located, but colocation means you can get away with not doing it and living in a broken state for longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;productivity--quality--focus&quot;&gt;Productivity &amp;amp; quality &amp;amp; focus&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to know that people are doing good work, right? And working hard often means looking like you’re working for a long period of time, i.e. sitting at your desk for at least the mandated company hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However. Being present is much easier to measure than productivity or quality, because to measure either or both of those you need to explicitly set out what quality means to you, and what productivity looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ramification of this is that you need to get better at setting goals and standards and deciding what you care about. Which, in turn, makes it easier for the people working in your company to make decisions and prioritise the things that ultimately matter most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different people have different daily rhythms that mean they’re more or less productive at certain times. Being able to schedule your own day (to some extent) enables folks to move their working time into those hours when they’re most likely to be in the right mindset and at the right energy level to be super productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that my ability to focus deeply is lowest immediately after lunch, so tend to schedule less solo work then in favour of more stimulating things (like 1:1s with my team, interviewing, dealing with my inbox backlog). I’m much better at tackling a big piece of work late afternoon - but childcare means leaving at 5pm if I’m on the pickup schedule. When I can, I tend to take the morning school run so that I’m not stuck racing out of the office when I’m hitting peak focus. At the same time, there have been many days when my brain has powered down partway through the day so I’ve used that time to commute home and then finish my day from home after a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer to work from home when I have no meetings at all so can do a whole distraction-free focussed-work day - knowing that if anything goes wrong I can jump on a videocall or be available on Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;legal-rights-too&quot;&gt;Legal rights too!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all (in the UK anyway) have the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; to formally request flexible working arrangements. There are a short list of reasons why a company can refuse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extra costs that will damage the business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the work cannot be reorganised among other staff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;people cannot be recruited to do the work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flexible working will affect quality and performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the business will not be able to meet customer demand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there’s a lack of work to do during the proposed working times&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the business is planning changes to the workforce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s it. So given that you’ll need to acquiesce to most flexible working requests, it’s quicker and easier to set up your boundaries and guidelines early, rather than in response to one of these requests. You’ll buy goodwill from your team, you’ll find it easier to hire, and you’ll remove the nerve-wracking tension for those in your team who have a genuine &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to work flexibly (vs a very valid preference!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ok-im-sold-how-do-we-get-there&quot;&gt;OK I’m sold, how do we get there?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m aware it can be a little daunting to start making a change like this. It takes a mindset shift as much as a policy change. But it doesn’t have to be everything at once, you can ease into it, and it’s good practice to set some guardrails and guidelines for comfort and to make the transition smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of the kind of internal policy you might consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we want you to be effective and productive while you are working, and we understand that for many people that means not working fixed hours at your desk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we expect you to average 40 hours a week if you are full-time. Some weeks will be longer, some will be shorter. It is up to you and your team how you manage this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as a company, we commit to holding recurring internal meetings between 11am and 4pm wherever possible, and generally avoid holding recurring internal meetings on Mondays and Fridays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we expect you to commit to shaping your working hours around internal meetings and any external meeting requirements. e.g. if you mostly work with people in a different time zone, you may wish to shift your typical working hours to accommodate that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we commit to taking reasonable steps to make it possible to do your work from a non-office location, e.g. we’ll equip our meeting rooms with a webcam and microphones, and every new joiner will receive a £50 contribution to headphones of your choice that enable you to dial in to meetings and be heard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we expect you to work in the office most days each week, unless agreed otherwise with your team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;you are responsible for ensuring that your working schedule does not impact your team’s ability to function effectively. Your team and manager are responsible for letting you know when your availability doesn’t meet the team’s needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can take a while to set guidelines and expectations that work for you, so it’ll always be an iterative process. However it’s well worth the time spent for the goodwill you’ll buy from the team, and the additional effectiveness you’ll all gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/flexible-working.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo by Aaron Burden on Unsplash: crayons and play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>maria campbell</name></author><summary type="html">I’m continually baffled by tech companies who set fixed working hours and expect everyone to work from the same place all the time. It feels old fashioned, in an industry that prides itself on innovation. And I’ve seen the advantages of flexible working play out - in terms of organisational effectiveness, as well as hiring &amp;amp; retention.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/flexible-working.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">askers &amp;amp; guessers / learning to say ‘no’ more often</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/askers-guessers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="askers &amp; guessers / learning to say 'no' more often" /><published>2019-07-15T22:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-15T22:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/askers-guessers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/askers-guessers">&lt;p&gt;Prioritising &amp;amp; delegating are hard. I struggle with both. I feel awkward (&amp;amp; even guilty!) saying “no” when someone makes a request of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I’m trying to teach myself at the moment is around saying “no” more often. I work best when I’m focussed on making forward progress on two things, with a handful of operational activities for context-switching satisfaction. Eg if I have two goals for the week plus 4 hours of managing my direct reports, 2 hours of exec- and people-team meetings, 5 hours of interviewing and 2 hours of presentation prep, I’m good. That’s enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more senior my roles have become, the more I’m finding myself with a team who can share the workload, and the more it’s become an ethical imperative to not overcommit either myself or my team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I take it so seriously when it comes to the endeavour of saying “no” more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a piece of leadership advice given regularly. For me, it’s usually been delivered by men who:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t typically have “office housework” (like taking notes and making coffee and booking meeting rooms) thrust upon them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t work in “support” functions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t work in a business function that’s seen as the home of “soft skills”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t have the same social expectations on them to be endlessly agreeable (else have euphemisms for “bitch” show up in their appraisals)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’d think saying no would be more important, justifiable, and internally acceptable as a woman who receives a lot of office housework asks and is the go-to person for things that fall in the bucket of not-my-job for basically the whole org. And yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-is-it-so-hard-to-say-no-sometimes&quot;&gt;Why is it so hard to say “no” sometimes?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a mental model which holds that there are two types of people: Askers and Guessers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both types categorise requests received &amp;amp; requests issued symmetrically. Askers assume everyone is an Asker, Guessers assume everyone is a Guesser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up as a Guesser, which means saying “no” to requests is hard! And I’m trying to become an Asker (which is also hard for different reasons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ok-cool-but-what-is-an-asker&quot;&gt;Ok cool but what is an Asker??&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Asker is someone who wonders if they can have something, then asks for it, then gets an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: I’m passing through town next week, can I crash at yours on Friday night?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: sorry, no, we have my in-laws staying so no space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: no worries! Let me know if you’re free for lunch instead otherwise I’ll catch you next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both are Askers, so, it’s simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-about-guessers&quot;&gt;What about Guessers?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Guesser, I would love to do the above. But first I must put myself in your place to determine whether my ask is reasonable. Will you think it’s rude? Would I be happy to offer you the same? Are you likely to say yes &lt;em&gt;and actually mean it&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there’s a heap more internal dialogue and worry and overthinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the above conversation might play out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: hiii how are you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: yeah great! Work’s going really well, we’re just back from a vacation too. How about you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: yeah all good! I’m actually going to be in town next week if you happen to be around?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: we’re around, it’d be great to see you. When are you free?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: oh I can do lunch basically any day and I’m free on Wednesday night too&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: cool, where are you staying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: work is putting me up most nights but I’m not sure about Wednesday yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: ah nice, your work are so cool, hope it’s a good hotel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: (&lt;em&gt;worries. They haven’t invited me to stay. That probably means I can’t crash at theirs. Best not to ask, that’d be awkward.&lt;/em&gt;) yeah I think it is. Any recommendations for Wednesday night?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2: (&lt;em&gt;sends links&lt;/em&gt;) we’d invite you to stay but my in-laws are over…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1: oh no of course, wouldn’t dream of putting you out, I’ll check out that link you sent. Thanks so much! (&lt;em&gt;worries. They haven’t suggested a time to meet up, I guess they don’t want to see me.&lt;/em&gt;) let me know if you do want to get lunch another day, sounds like you’re really busy though. Bye!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Painful, right? Because 1 is a Guesser and 2 is an Asker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They reach the same outcome but there’s extra stress and &lt;em&gt;awkward&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;feelings&lt;/em&gt; and significantly more messages exchanged. And more cringe for you, reading the imaginary transcript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re already identifying &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; with one of these two types you’ll know what’s coming…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;its-frustrating-when-we-clash&quot;&gt;It’s frustrating when we clash&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an Asker, Guessers feel super indirect and waffly. You know they want something, but they won’t just front up and tell you. They take forever to make their request, and take a “no” pretty hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet it’s &lt;em&gt;even worse&lt;/em&gt; the other way around, because the social contract is skewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Askers evaluate each request and conclude either yes or no. Guessers take each request with the extra assumption that the person asking &lt;em&gt;has already dismissed&lt;/em&gt; obvious objections and concluded that a “yes” is the reasonable outcome here (otherwise why would you ask??!), so it’s hard to say “no” to a request made in this context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Guesser, Askers feel abrasive and make sometimes unreasonable requests - because they haven’t prescreened them (because why should you need to??!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, as someone in a leadership role, you’re told to say “no” more if you want to succeed, and it’s especially hard as a Guesser because it takes some mental effort to overturn the impulse that tells you requests should be ratified or modified. You need to learn, then understand, then teach yourself that a rejection is a completely acceptable outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;managing-the-clash&quot;&gt;Managing the clash&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m afraid I don’t have answers here because I’m slowly training myself to approach life as an Asker. Especially when I know I’m interacting with another Asker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship, the asymmetry of the social contract around requests, is often much easier to manage when negotiating on behalf of a party that’s not yourself, with a non-human party (eg a contract on behalf of a business you work for, houseshare rental fees for you &amp;amp; your flatmates).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes some work, though, when you find yourself engaging with a Guesser while posing as an Asker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the receiving end, it’s important to be mindful of the likelihood that the request had been pre-screened. You may need to surface, or even invite, the request. And to soften the “no” so it’s received but the Guesser doesn’t feel rebuffed or refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the requesting end, knowing that a “no” is less forthcoming means prenegotiating or caveating, because the Guesser feels compelled to say “yes” to your presumably reasonable request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;as-a-leader&quot;&gt;As a leader…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s your responsibility to build processes and structures and rhythms that work for both your Askers and your Guessers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every company I’ve ever worked for, I’ve pushed hard for a rhythm of proactive pay review so that nobody needs to ask, and nobody is rewarded or penalised for being one type or the other. Same for promotions, feedback, training &amp;amp; recognition. Clear boundaries and policies help Guessers to navigate their own personal internal approval process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a manager, I’m doing my best to be an Asker on behalf of my team and an advocate for my Guessers to the rest of the business. I’m also trying to coach both to understand and empathise with the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest thing about saying “no” more often is that it requires you to build a culture where Askers are safe to make requests without being judged as too demanding or arrogant, and Guessers feel safe enough to make their requests and receive a comfortable no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would, of course, be easier if we were all Askers, but a large part of being a person, working with people, in organisations made up of people, is examining and understanding tendencies &amp;amp; behaviours and doing our best to level the playing field wherever we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/askers-guessers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo by Clem Onojeghuo on Unsplash: guess how many sweets or ask for a sweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>maria campbell</name></author><summary type="html">Prioritising &amp;amp; delegating are hard. I struggle with both. I feel awkward (&amp;amp; even guilty!) saying “no” when someone makes a request of me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/askers-guessers.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">final questions / what to ask at the end of an interview</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/final-questions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="final questions / what to ask at the end of an interview" /><published>2019-07-10T11:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T11:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/final-questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/final-questions/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time interviewing. I’ve been interviewing regularly as part of my job for years, and regularly spend 3-10 hours interviewing in any given week. I shadow and coach interviewers, with a focus on making the time we spend interviewing more useful and enjoyable for all participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that has varied wildly across the 1000+ candidates I’ve interviewed is what questions they ask when given time at the end of the session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking good questions shows curiosity &amp;amp; engagement, and it’s hard (as an interviewer) to determine how objectively significant or relevant it is when a candidate has good questions, or no questions. I find that the types of questions a candidate asks says a lot about what they care about. It’s difficult not to bias towards preferring candidates who ask good questions; which is unfair if we as interviewers are making it hard for candidates to feel comfortable asking what they want to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When coaching interviewers, I’ve settled on a few tactics to ensure that the candidate feels able to ask whatever they like. I know some interviewers make this intimidating, and “do you have any questions?” is one of the &lt;em&gt;least&lt;/em&gt; inviting ways to ask this, especially to a nervous candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to ask:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you want to know about (company)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What worries you about us, as a team or a business or a place to spend the next few years of your career?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there anything you’d like to know that hasn’t been covered yet?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These, in my experience, result in more questions from the candidate, and a more engaging conversation around their potential concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of all this interviewing and interview design, from the company perspective, results in pulling together question banks to cover off certain interview criteria. And when I set out on my own job search recently, I found myself building interview kits for myself as candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the generalised version of my interview question bank, specifically for candidates - the questions you should consider asking every interviewer you meet when changing role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these are the inverse of what I’ve asked candidates for management roles; some I’ve been asked and borrowed(!); some are questions I have used myself in “networking” contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;your-future-manager&quot;&gt;Your future manager:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you describe your leadership style?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What personality types do you find easiest to manage?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you’re hiring, what general qualities do you look for?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you think will be the biggest challenge here for me in particular?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you see us working together?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you structure your team?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the planning &amp;amp; communication rhythms within the team?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you tell me about a recent mistake or crisis or something that went wrong?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you support my development?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the most useful feedback you’ve had from the team?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you approach giving critical feedback?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which team member’s progression are you most proud of?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you’re prioritising the team’s work, what criteria do you use?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you err on the side of experience or potential when hiring for your team?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why are you hiring for this role now?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would my first month here look like?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you expect this role to change over the next 6-9 months?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you measure success in the team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;your-future-team-mates&quot;&gt;Your future team-mates:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s surprised you the most since you joined?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does the team make decisions?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the dynamics like in the team?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does conflict look like in this team? Can you give me a recent example?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the most useful feedback you’ve had from your manager?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you find frustrating about working here?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What have you learnt about yourself while working here?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are you most looking for in this role - how would this person help you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you &amp;amp; I work together, if I join?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the biggest challenge for the team right now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;culture&quot;&gt;Culture:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you all communicate with each other?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roughly how much time do you spend in meetings each day?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much time do you spend with people in different functions?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does recognition work here?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does the company support building team camaraderie?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much transparency is there around decisions made at the exec level?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do different teams interact with each other? If I want some input from design, how would I make that happen?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the overall company goals for this quarter?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you talk me through an org chart? (What’s working well about the org structure?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you could change one thing about the company, what would it be?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many people have left in the last year? Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you tell me about a tough decision made at a company-level recently?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does “diversity” mean here?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does anyone work part-time, do you have any parents?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you value, as a company?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the biggest differences between here and the last place you worked?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was the main reason you joined?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;business&quot;&gt;Business:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your main acquisition channels?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the biggest challenges to getting new customers on board?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(if sales) What’s the average deal size?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your revenue at the moment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many months of runway does the company have?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the long-term goal for the business?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Of your competitors, which one do you think is the highest risk to your business? Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you expect headcount to change over the next six months?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your sales strategy? How do you expect that to change over the next year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the make-up of the leadership team?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who’s on the Board? How involved are they?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which business functions have you over-invested in? Why those?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-quick-note-on-research&quot;&gt;A quick note on research&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t ask questions that you can look up online! I’d recommend looking at LinkedIn (the /people page in the company listing is super useful); Crunchbase; DueDil; AngelList; and of course the company blog &amp;amp; about page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work out who’s interviewing you, look them up on LinkedIn to see if there’s anything particularly pertinent in their background that you’d like to ask about (e.g. maybe they changed teams while at the company). Slice up your questions so you can focus on asking the most relevant interviewer and therefore getting the most useful answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, now you have a ton of things to ask, remember you’ve probably only got 10 mins with each interviewer to find this stuff out - prioritise the things that matter most to you, not just the questions that make you think you sound smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/final-questions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo by Tachina Lee on Unsplash: woman thinking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>maria campbell</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve spent a lot of time interviewing. I’ve been interviewing regularly as part of my job for years, and regularly spend 3-10 hours interviewing in any given week. I shadow and coach interviewers, with a focus on making the time we spend interviewing more useful and enjoyable for all participants.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/final-questions.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">acceptable transgressions / body hair &amp;amp; your greatest weakness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/acceptable-transgressions" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="acceptable transgressions / body hair &amp; your greatest weakness" /><published>2019-07-02T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/acceptable-transgressions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/acceptable-transgressions">&lt;p&gt;One of the basic interview prep pieces of advice is to rehearse an answer for “what’s your greatest weakness?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; dislike this question: because only &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; answers are allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So often it’s asked because the interviewer has pulled it from a list of things to ask in interview, and so often it’s answered with something glib and unrevealing. You ask the question, I say the thing I prepared, we move on. You haven’t learnt anything about me, you haven’t prepared for receiving this info, you aren’t going to work with me to plan how we mitigate or improve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t dispute that it’s useful to know someone’s skill-gaps, to verify their level of self-awareness, to gauge how humble they are, to learn how receptive they are to feedback from others, to understand their learning &amp;amp; self-development plans and approach. But with this question, and the way it’s deployed, you won’t get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the many many many thinkpieces and advice snippets for how to share your Greatest Weakness focus on palatable gaps. Say, maybe you’re a perfectionist. Maybe you just care too much. Maybe you love to help others so sometimes have to work long hours to achieve your goals. Maybe you have a visionary understanding of where the industry is about to pivot to and you’re only just starting to get ahead of the curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like body hair. Women’s body hair in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-body-hair-that-were-allowed&quot;&gt;The body hair that we’re allowed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We celebrate women (white cis women who are conventionally attractive according western beauty norms) when they transgress the ideal of hairlessness. Hey &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teenvogue.com/story/halsey-unshaven-armpits-rolling-stone-cover&quot;&gt;Halsey didn’t shave her underarms&lt;/a&gt; and she’s on the cover of Rolling Stone with her armpits out, that’s a powerful feminist move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even unshaven legs are a symbol of non-conforming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are heaps of “my story” pieces in women’s magazines both online and offline about why someone chose not to remove all their body hair BUT they are all focussed on the acceptable transgressions, the palatable decisions to diverge from the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ladies, if you’re “beautiful” enough, you can decide to not shave your legs or underarms. That’s the message we take away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet we don’t even mention upper lip hair; toe hair; that weird long hair that grows out of the middle of your forehead; nipple hair; back hair. And we CERTAINLY don’t engage with the idea that maybe it’s a bold feminist choice to leave the hair to grow as it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re so focussed on performing vulnerability, performing boldness, that we don’t dig deep and truly examine these things and benefit from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I want to remove my bodyhair? If only partly, can I focus on the parts that are irritating or time consuming, not the parts deemed socially permissible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-greatest-weaknesses-that-were-allowed&quot;&gt;The Greatest Weaknesses that we’re allowed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find ourselves in the same position when confronted with “what’s your greatest weakness?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are weaknesses we are allowed to have, allowed to share. And others that we can’t touch on even when they’re true, even when they’re important for our future manager to know, even when we’re still eminently hirable with these weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody is perfect, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I want to acknowledge my imperfections? If so, can I do so in a way that imparts useful directional info to a future manager? Is it not also harmful to me to perform invulnerability when I’ll need this person, this future manger, to support and guide me to level up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please stop asking “what’s your greatest weakness”. Please stop preparing glib answers. Let’s have a real conversation instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-instead&quot;&gt;What instead?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what you want with your body hair, folks, and stop casting judgement on others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, perhaps more pertinently, interview better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the questions I’ve used to achieve the goal that I think we ought to be aiming for when we consider asking this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what have you learnt about yourself in the last year?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how would you manager describe you? Would your coworkers say anything different? Why do you think that?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What skills do you want to learn or improve here?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you join us, how would you want us to support your personal development?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the most useful feedback you’ve received? How have you used that feedback?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we’re building a well-rounded team, what skills should we look for in the next person we hire to work alongside you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you want to get better at?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you approach new problems that our completely out of your comfort zone? Do you have an example?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about a time when you got stuck at work. How did you get past it? Who helped you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking back at the job ad for this role, which parts do you think you’ll find most challenging?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviewees: flip it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick one of the above, answer that instead, then ask the person interviewing you how they have supported someone in mitigating or overcoming their biggest weakness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we can have real conversations, learn things about each other, and stop doing the dance where we say things for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/acceptable-transgressions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo by Mel Poole on Unsplash: hair removal paraphenalia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>maria campbell</name></author><summary type="html">One of the basic interview prep pieces of advice is to rehearse an answer for “what’s your greatest weakness?”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/acceptable-transgressions.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">connective learning / mis-spending my training budget</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/connective-learning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="connective learning / mis-spending my training budget" /><published>2019-06-30T09:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T09:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/connective-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/connective-learning">&lt;p&gt;I decided to change jobs a couple of months ago, so spent a bunch of time interviewing and really learnt a lot about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few pieces of interesting feedback that were remarkably consistent across every person I interviewed with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a different perspective / think about problems differently to them.
This has been a recurring theme in feedback from people I work with too (and friends!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is unclear what how I approach my own personal development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this particularly interesting because I consider myself to be a curious person who spends a lot of time learning, and I really value the pursuit of learning - it’s fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I concluded that I need to get better at articulating how I think about learning: particularly as a People leader, where I’ll be responsible for helping everyone in the company learn and develop! So I’ve spent some time considering this and uncovered the empiric truth of how I approach learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this exercise really helpful, so am sharing here both the way that I thought about this, and the conclusions I came to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem-finding-problem-solving&quot;&gt;Problem finding, problem solving&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was fortunate enough to sneak into some of the talks at the exceptional Lead Developer conference in London. One really stuck with me - it hugely clarified something I’d been thinking about but hadn’t developed a mental model for yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please either pause and watch it:  or at least open it in a new tab and promise me you’ll watch it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to earlier this month, when I picked up Dan Pink’s book To Sell Is Human. In one of the chapters, he pitches to his reader that the modern world of selling requires becoming a problem &lt;em&gt;finder&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Problem finders] sort through vast amounts of information and inputs, often from multiple disciplines; experiment with a variety of different approaches; are willing to switch directions in the course of a project; and often take longer than their counterparts to complete their work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;becoming-a-good-cook&quot;&gt;Becoming a good cook&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to this morning. I’m on my way to a knife skills course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like food. I enjoy the creativity of making something delicious, and the gratification of spending time making a tangible thing then consuming it. There’s something around the instant feedback loop there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first moved out of my parents’ house and became responsible for feeding myself, I concluded that I needed to become a good cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of caveats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I didn’t really learn to cook at home; my mum wasn’t super experimental, so taught me the basics but in a very intuitive way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I find it hard to follow recipes - it limits my understanding of the WHY (&amp;amp; reminds me of learning cookery at school where I spent about a year fucking up white sauce and pastry because I didn’t &lt;em&gt;get it&lt;/em&gt; enough to know what was important and how to fix mistakes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I set about achieving this goal of &lt;em&gt;becoming a good cook&lt;/em&gt; through various different strands - assembling the building blocks or grammar &amp;amp; syntax of food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of the things I undertook, semi-deliberately, over the last 15(!!) years in order to become someone who can now cook well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sought out nice restaurants within my budget and ate things I didn’t know how to cook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read menus and collected themes of ingredients that people use together regularly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;started drinking my way through red wine and reading the labels to understand what I liked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read a paper about soil, sun and climate change in relation to wine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spent a few hours browsing in a book store to understand what combinations of foods cropped up in which geographic areas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read more about climate, soil and local vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;moved in with a man who has strong feelings about texture in food&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;started trialling substitutions in my regular dishes to see what worked well (and what was actually disastrous or inedible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nikisegnit.com/the-flavour-thesaurus&quot;&gt;The Flavour Thesaurus&lt;/a&gt; by Nikki Segnit and read it cover to cover to cement the themes of flavour pairings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watched my scientist sister cooking a roast dinner and how she thinks about heat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had a baby and observed his approach to self-feeding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read a series of papers about heat, which materials conduct, pre-heating, effect of moisture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read The Omnivore’s Dilemma by Michael Pollan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read the counterargument to this, Eating Animals by Jonathan Safran Foer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sniffed a bunch of spices at a spice market on vacation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;took up origami (in the hope it would help me build the discipline of recipe-following!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saltfatacidheat.com/&quot;&gt;Salt Fat Acid Heat&lt;/a&gt; by Samin Nosrat (twice)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read a bunch of vegan blogs to get a better understanding of the politics of food&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read Sight Smell Touch Taste Sound by Sybil Kapoor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;signed up for a knife skills class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bought (but haven’t read yet!) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nikisegnit.com/lateral-cooking&quot;&gt;Lateral Cooking&lt;/a&gt;, also by Nikki Segnit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these things have help me build up a solid foundation on which I can build connections, understanding the history and politics and geography of food; cuisine, nutrition, balance; how the senses interplay in eating; the science behind how certain processes work.
Which had given me a super strong, well-informed approach to building meals that &lt;em&gt;just work&lt;/em&gt; and can be cooked free-hand (because while my origami game is strong I still rebel whenever I attempt to follow a recipe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;another-shorter-example&quot;&gt;Another, shorter example&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken a similar approach to art:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hanging out in galleries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning where pigments come from&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;studying aesthetics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading The Story of Art by EH Gombrich&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;modelling for life drawing classes and listening intently (in between naps)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading some pop science articles to understand how humans perceive colour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;taking a course on contemporary art philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading about the history of colour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visiting more galleries &amp;amp; exhibitions with engaged friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;deliberately seeking out artists I love in curated exhibitions whose topics are unfamiliar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;taking up painting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;picking up some paint by numbers versions of famous paintings to understand how to paint nuanced colours &amp;amp; shade (I freaking love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://faradayscienceshop.com/collections/van-go-paint-by-number-kits/&quot;&gt;Van-Go kits&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visiting yet more galleries….&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a web of perspectives, drawing connections between them, identifying and honing in on the empty spaces and starting to sketch in what’s missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-what-does-this-mean&quot;&gt;So what does this mean?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This connective dabbling, building a web of learning and perspective, is how learning through my career has worked too. Getting a deep understanding of analogous &amp;amp; adjacent spaces and combining these in between from a slightly askew perspective to end up with something built from scratch, ground-up, without completely ignoring conventional wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much of this is because I ended up studying philosophy for three years, and so dig deeply into epistemology, theory of knowledge and interlocking web-based models of truth and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the startup world, we have a huge opportunity to do things differently. We can reexamine existing models and fill out the gaps, we can dig deeper to find the problem that actually matters and build a solution that works for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conventional business, if learning is a priority at all it’s very linear. It’s relatively easy to take a course that is obviously directly related to your role and will obviously directly impact your performance. But this isn’t how everyone learns. I’d love to build a world where we make space for people to learn in this connective way. Where &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; your receptionist should take a user experience design course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I think if I told most companies that to help me learn to cook I need a JSTOR subscription, a topographical map of Europe and a case of wine, they’d laugh. But here we are; so why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/connective-learning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My current reading list&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>maria campbell</name></author><summary type="html">I decided to change jobs a couple of months ago, so spent a bunch of time interviewing and really learnt a lot about myself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/connective-learning.jpg" /></entry></feed>